They came for the gold. They stayed for the adventure.
The Road to El Dorado is a family, adventure,
animation film directed by Bibo Bergeron.
Stowing away after a failed con, a pair of swindlers end up on El Dorado, the fabled "city of gold", where
they quickly get in over their heads when they are mistaken as gods by the inhabitants.
Miguel  (voice), played by Kenneth Branagh.
Tulio (voice), played by Kevin Kline.
Chel (voice), played by Rosie Perez.
Tzekel-Kan (voice), played by Armand Assante.
Chief (voice), played by Edward James Olmos.
Cortes (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
The Road to El Dorado is a 2000 American animated musical adventure comedy film directed by Eric "Bibo" Bergeron and Don Paul, from a
screenplay by Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio, as well as additional sequences directed by Will Finn and David Silverman.
Starring the voices of Kevin Kline, Kenneth Branagh, Rosie Perez, Armand Assante, and Edward James Olmos, the film follows a pair of con artists who, after winning the
map to El Dorado in Spain, wash ashore in the New World; the map leads the two men to the city of El Dorado, where its inhabitants mistake them for gods.
The soundtrack features an instrumental score composed by Hans Zimmer and
John Powell, and songs written by Elton John and Tim Rice.
John also periodically narrates the story in song throughout the film.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation and released by DreamWorks Pictures, it
was the third animated feature produced by the studio.
The Road to El Dorado was theatrically released in
the United States on March 31, 2000.
It received mixed reviews from critics and underperformed at the box office, grossing $76
million worldwide on a production budget of approximately $95 million.
Zimmer's work on the score, however, received praise and earned him the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best
Score alongside his work on Gladiator, another DreamWorks film, at the 6th Critics' Choice Awards.
Despite its initial reception, reevaluation in later years has
resulted in The Road to El Dorado becoming a cult classic.
The film explores themes of gold, horse, cartoon, musical, con artist.
The tone is lighthearted.